# Nicolas Taconet

# Current position

Since 2017 **PhD candidate in Environmental Economics**, Centre International de Recherche en Environmement et Développement (CIRED), *Essays on the economic impacts of climate change*. Supervisor: C. Guivarch. Research interests: Integrated Assessment Modeling, Climate change, Optimal taxation, Inequality and environment, Scenario analysis.

#### Education

- 2017 MPP in Sustainable Development, École des Ponts ParisTech.
- 2016 MSc in Economics of Environment, Energy and Transport, École Polytechnique.
- 2014 BSc in Advanced Engineering, École Polytechnique.

## Work Experience

- March–July French Ministry for the Environment, Economic Policy Analyst.
  - $2018 \quad \text{Worked on socio-technical uncertainties in low carbon pathways using Dynamic Marginal Abatement Curves}.$
  - 2016–2017 **Agence Française de Développement**, Research Assistant for the Chief Economist.

    Studied carbon prices compatible with Paris Agreement, using coupling between macro (GEMMES) and bottom-up (POLES) models.
- March-July CIRED, Research fellow.
  - 2016 Developed a stochastic Integrated Assessment Model using dynamic programming.
- March-Aug Environmental Defense Fund, Research Assistant for G. Wagner.
  - 2015 Literature review on Emissions Trading Systems for World Bank-led Handbook
- Summer 2014 Climate Economics Chair, Research intern.

Research on environmental valuation methods and discrete choice experiments in public policy.

#### Articles

In Progress Optimal climate policy under inter and intra-generational inequalities: revisiting Schelling's conjecture, with Céline Guivarch and Aurélie Méjean.

Under review Climate change and inequality between countries: influence of climate change impacts and mitigation costs on inequalities in the 21st century, with Aurélie Méjean and Céline Guivarch, Draft upon request.

Under review Social Cost of Carbon under stochastic tipping points: does risk play a role?, with Céline Guivarch and Antonin Pottier, Link to FAERE Working paper.

#### Book chapters

In progress Inégalités Internationales et Changement climatique.

with Céline Guivarch, in Numéro Spécial "Ecologie et inégalité", Revue de l'OFCE (January 2020)

In progress International inequality and climate change.

with Céline Guivarch, in Routledge Handbook of the Political Economy of the Environment (2020)

#### Oral presentations

- 2019 FAERE (Rennes), CIRED Summer School, Journées Louis André Gérard Varet (Aix-en-Provence), AMSE Spring School (Marseille), CIRED Séminaire Doctorant.
- Journées Climat et Impact Université (Université Paris-Sud), IAMC2019 (Séville), Summer School EAERE-FEEM-VIU (Venice), International Energy Workshop (Gothenburg).
- 2016 IAMC2016 (Beijing).

# Teaching

2018-2019 École des Ponts ParisTech.

Tutoring of students' projects on Cost Benefit Analysis (20h)

#### Agro ParisTech.

Integrated Assessment Models: DICE (6h), Tutoring of a student project on climate impact modeling in an IAM

#### 2017-2018 Université Sorbonne Paris Cité.

Environmental Economics (36h)

#### École des Ponts ParisTech.

Cost-Benefit Analysis (10h), Industrial Organization (10h)

### Miscellaneous

Languages French (native language), English (fluent), German (C2), Italian (B2)

Computer R, Python, SciLab, Stata

Volunteering public writer (Montreuil), tutoring in prisons (GENEPI)

Hobbies Sports and cinema